Anthony Marshall - Resume

Personal Details

Address: Point Chevalier, Auckland, NZ: Nationality: New Zealand Email Address: anthonymarshall@gmail.com: Phone: 027 658 4855

LinkedIn Profile: linkedIn Profile: linkedin.com/in/anthonymarshallnz

Portfolio Site : anthonymarshall.io

About Me

I'm a software developer who has 17 years of commercial experience building many successful web, desktop, mobile and server based systems for a wide variety of industries, such as government, utilities, finance, marketing/advertising, retail and real estate.

Outside of work, I'm an avid sports fan with a great passion for tennis and running. I am a member of the Point Chevalier Tennis Club.

Education

2000 – 2003 : Auckland University of Technology

Bachelor of Applied Science (Software Development pathway)

2021 : <u>Microsoft Certified Data Analyst Associate</u>

Certification



Software Technology Experience

	Years Experience								
Technology	< 1	1	2	3	4	5	6+		
C# .Net							•		
Java					•				
PHP (with Laravel)					•				
Sharepoint				•					
Power BI				•					
Web frontend (HTML\CSS\JS\SASS\React)							•		
SQL Server							•		
MySQL / Postgresql					•				
Oracle 9i & 10g		•							
Elasticsearch		•							

GIT / CI/CD (Teamcity / Jenkins/ Docker/ Gitlab CI)					•
Linux Administration			•		
Technical Lead			•		
Agile development (with Jira)				•	
Amazon AWS			•		
Microsoft Azure	•				

Other Skills

- Advocate for Software Development best practices. E.g SOLID, DDD, TDD
- Exceptional verbal and written communication skills.
- Excellent time management skills and practices.
- Extensive client liaison and user training experience.
- Can quickly learn and adapt new development technologies.
- Experience managing and mentoring developers
- Ability to architect simple technical solutions for complex problems.

Work Experience

New Zealand Government

October 2017 - Present

L3 Software Engineer

Working as a senior engineer focused on building and maintaining data pipelines and integrations, custom desktop and web applications, and BI tools.

Tech stack used in this role: Java, .Net, Sharepoint, Elasticsearch and Power BI

Please contact me for more details about this role.

Datacom NZ (<u>datacom.co.nz</u>)

February 2017 – October 2017

Full Stack Developer

Worked primarily for Datacom's client, Barfoot & Thompson.

Key achievement was being the lead developer on Barfoot's SalesKit project from conception to release. This is an interactive web application used by sales agents to create and design professionally printed promotional material and property listing documentation.

Built using React, Redux, .Net, Sql Server. This product has proven to be highly successful to Barfoot & Thompson, and is actively used by the business today.

BBD Perfect Storm London (<u>bbdperfectstorm.com</u>) (formerly Suburb Design London <u>wearesuburb.com</u>)

September 2012 – January 2017

<u>Technical Lead / Senior Developer</u>

Dual role of Technical Lead and Senior Developer (50/50 time split). Key responsibilities were to develop front and back end web and desktop applications, manage the development team (4 devs plus freelancers), define development processes, write technical documentation and be the technical contact for clients.

Clients that I have worked with in this role were Investec, BP, Cadburys, Samsung, Converse, Japanese Tobacco International, De Beers and Kinder.

Tech stack used in this role: C#, Asp.net, WPF, Sql Server, Episerver, PHP, Laravel, Magento, MySql, Postgres, HTML/CSS/JS, SASS, Angular 1 & 2, React, Git, AWS, Jenkins

Candi London (candi.co.uk)

June 2012 – August 2012

Freelance Senior .Net Developer (contract)

Digital agency servicing Morrisons supermarket. My role here was to help build new modules for the Morrison's online shopping website (www.morrisons.co.uk) and add integration with SalesForce

Tech stack used in this role: C#, Asp.net, Sql Server, Episerver, HTML/CSS/JS, Teamcity

Suburb Design London (<u>wearesuburb.com</u>)

January 2012 – June 2012

Freelance Senior .Net Developer (contract)

Suburb are a digital agency based in London who specialise in interactive art direction and design, website design and development, and social media app development.

I am was working here as a contract developer and have been involved in a number of projects coding (front and back-end) highly interactive, advertising campaign based websites and Facebook applications.

The fast paced nature of projects and tight deadlines in digital agencies such as Suburb allowed me to demonstrate that I was capable of producing quality code in a timely fashion to meet project demands.

Tech stack used in this role: C#, Asp.net, Sql Server, HTML/CSS/JS, LESS, SVN

AIMIA (aimia.com)

June 2007 - October 2011

(formerly Carlson Marketing Ltd)

Senior Analyst Programmer

AIMIA (formerly Carlson Marketing Ltd) is a world leading provider of customer loyalty programmes. For our credit card loyalty systems, I helped build points engines (processing 100,000+ credit card transactions per day) and full e-commerce point redemption websites for clients such as Vodafone, Westpac, ASB, ANZ and Pfizer.

Systems that I have worked on include:

- <u>www.hotpoints.co.nz</u> Westpac bank's customer loyalty points programme
- www.truerewards.co.nz ASB bank's customer loyalty points programme

Tech stack used in this role : ASP.Net, C#, SQL Server, SQL DTS and SSIS, Crystal, Kentico CMS

Key Responsibilities:

- Application development of high traffic, front-end and back-end transactional systems
- Database design and development
- B2B EDI design, development and implementation

- Technical documentation
- Implementation of multi-lingual systems
- Training and support for junior developers
- Liaising with external clients and in-house account managers
- Migration of legacy systems into modern development platforms (e.g Fox Pro -> .Net)

Kinetiq Ltd (<u>www.kinetiq.com</u>)

January 2005 – June 2007

<u>Analyst Programmer</u>

Kinetiq Ltd is a provider of web and desktop based data management solutions for the international energy market. In this role I helped build energy-usage monitoring and billing management system.

Tech stack used in this role: ASP.Net, C#.Net, SQL Server and Oracle 10g

Edis International Ltd

May 2004 – December 2004

Software Developer

In this position I was hired as a software developer to work on developing B2B EDI message translation applications that work closely with various ERP systems. Messaging standards that I have become familiar with in this role were XML, ANSI x12 and EDIFACT. I was also responsible for other tasks within the organisation such as the development of EdisInternational.com website and software product testing.

Tech stack used in this role: VB6, VB.Net, ASP, Pervasive and SQL Server.

Blueday Ltd

May 2003 – May 2004

Software Developer

This was my first full-time position as an IT professional. I specialised in web development for small to medium sized businesses.

Tech stack used in this role: Classic ASP, ASP.net and SQL Server.

Online Talent Agency

August 2002 – July 2003

Student software developer

In the final year of my degree, I undertook a research and development project for an Auckland-based talent agency, Background Talent. They specialise in managing extras, actors and production crews for TV and Film

For them I developed a web-based system, which enabled my client to managing talent and jobs more efficiently.

Key technologies used in this position: PHP, MySQL and Apache.

References

Available on request